stayclassy.org 2017-03-28

# Privacy Policy | Classy

Classy Inc. (referred to throughout as " **us** ," " **we** ," " **our** ," etc.), is the owner and operator of the www.classy.org website, a fundraising platform for nonprofits. This Privacy Policy applies to the www.classy.org website, any subdomains thereof, any API integrations or widgets we offer, and any other websites or webpages we own or operate that include a link to this policy (all of which together are referred to as the " **Website** "). Although we provide shorter answers to privacy questions on the Website in order to be helpful, this Privacy Policy is the exclusive and authoritative source of our privacy practices. Please keep in mind that this Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites, which may be accessible from the Website. External websites may have data collection, storage, and use practices and policies that differ materially from those conta sned here. 

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we do so, we will notify you by posting the date of the last change or amendment at the top of this page. You agree that this method of notice is sufficient and that you will regularly check this Privacy Policy to see if updates or changes have been made. 

##  What Types of Information Do You Collect? 

**Traffic Data.** As is true of most websites, we automatically collect certain information when you visit our Website. This information includes: (i) IP addresses, (ii) domain servers, (iii) types of computers accessing the Website, (iv) types of web browsers used to access the Website, (v) referring/exit pages, (vi) data about usage patterns throughout the Website (e.g. click rates on different links etc.). Information of this type (" **Traffic Data** ") is anonymous information that does not personally identify you but is helpful for us to improve the business performance and user experience of the Website. 

**Personal Information.** In order for you to make donations through the Website, register with the Website, purchase tickets or registrations through the Website, RSVP to free events posted on the Website, or take certain other actions on the Website (e.g. contacting us through forms, etc.) we require you to provide us with information that personally identifies you (" **Personal Information** "). Personal Information includes the following types of data: 

⋅ Contact Data such as name, mailing address, e-mail address, and Classy user-name, account number, and password 

⋅ Financial Data such as your account or credit card number 

⋅ Demographic Data such as your zip code, age, and gender 

⋅ Company Data such as your business name, size, and business type 

⋅ Activity Data such as your donation history, fundraising history, events attended, etc. 

##  How do you collect Traffic Data? 

As is true of most websites, we use cookies to collect Traffic Data related to the Website. We use another company to place cookies on your computer to compile this non-personally identifiable information so we can aggregate statistical information about usage of the Website. 

The Website also contains web beacons, which are electronic images that are used along with cookies to compile statistics so we can analyze how the Website is being used. Our e-mails may also contain web beacons so we can track how many people open the message or click on links within the message. This information helps us improve our communication and marketing efforts. 

We use a third party to gather information on how you and others are using the Website. By using this service we are able (for example) to see how many people visited a given page or clicked on a given link. This information helps us optimize the performance of the Website. We also use cookies to serve ads through third party ad network services to people who have visited our Website (" **Retargeting Ads** "). These Retargeting Ads will be viewable on other websites that are part of the ad network. Your browser likely contains controls for deleting or disabling cookies; however, your experience on the Website may be impacted if cookies are disabled. 

##  Is my Personal Information kept confidential? 

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your Personal Information private and will not share it with other third parties unless such disclosure is necessary to: (i) comply with a court order or other legal process, (ii) to protect our rights or property, or (iii) to enforce our Terms of Service. Please keep in mind that while we take reasonable precautions to safeguard your Personal Information no amount of protection can guarantee its security. 

##  How does Classy use my Personal Information? 

We use your information in a variety of ways to help us run the Website. Here are some of the ways we use your information: 

To send you receipts 

To send you updates about the Website 

To send you updates about activity on the Website related to you 

To send newsletters 

To administer your account 

To respond to customer service inquiries 

To send marketing materials 

To improve our Website and marketing efforts 

To administer the CLASSY Awards or other promotions you have entered 

##  How do your email communications work? 

We send out various emails to clients and others who interact with the Website, such as emails about new blog posts, product releases, or special events or promotions (" **Marketing Emails** "). Nonprofits that register with the Website will automatically be subscribed to receive certain Marketing Emails. Aside from those registering with the Website, you must opt in to receive Marketing Emails. 

Marketing Emails contain an unsubscribe option which you can follow at any point if you wish to stop receiving some, or all, Marketing Emails. If you have received our Marketing Emails mistakenly, or wish to stop receiving them, you can also contact us at [help@classy.org](mailto:info@classy.org) and we will remove you from our list. 

The Website also allows nonprofit clients to send various transactional (e.g. automated donation receipts etc.) and outreach emails (together " **Client Emails** "). Unless such Client Emails are excepted as part of an ongoing commercial relationship, or otherwise, by CANSPAM, they will contain an unsubscribe link. 

As part of a nonprofit client's use of the Website, individual supporters of the nonprofit may also send emails through the Website (" **Supporter Emails** "). For example, personal fundraisers may send messages to their contacts through the Website in order to ask people to visit their fundraising page and donate. They may also send emails to update donors or to thank donors for their gifts. Supporter Emails sent through the Website will have an unsubscribe link. 

Please keep in mind that, notwithstanding the foregoing, we have no control over emails sent through third party emailing applications. 

##  Who has access to my Credit Card Number? 

We do not process any underlying payments facilitated by the Website; payments are processed by our partner Internet Payment Service Providers, currently PayPal, WePay, and Authorize.net (each a " **Payments Partner** "). Financial data you input to consummate a transaction is encrypted using SSL technology and sent to a Payments Partner. For recurring donations your Financial and Contact data is stored by a Payment Partner in accordance with industry standards. Only the Payment Partner has access to your credit card number. We do not have access to your credit card number. Data handled by a Payment Partner is subject to that Payments Partner's terms and privacy policy. 

We use Chargify (www.chargify.com) to process monthly payments made by nonprofits that purchase subscription plans or upgrades from us. If you purchase a subscription plan, your purchase will be made on an SSL encrypted page hosted by Chargify and the information you submit will be stored by Chargify in accordance with industry standards. Data handled by Chargify is subject to Chargify's terms and privacy policy. 

##  Who has access to my Personal Information (Except for Credit Card #)? 

We share your Personal information with other business partners who assist us in performing core services (such as hosting, data storage, and security) related to the operation of the Website. These business partners only use your Personal Information to perform these core services, which are necessary for the orderly operation of the Website. 

Any organization you make a contribution to, or purchase from, through the Website will have access to your Personal Information (except for your credit card number); note that making a donation "anonymous" only hides your donation from public activity feeds, not the underlying charitable beneficiary. 

If you donate anonymously through a personal or team fundraising page, your personal information will not be shared with either the individual fundraiser or the team fundraising captain. If you make a donation to an individual fundraiser but do not donate anonymously, then the person who created the fundraising page will also have access to your Personal Information (except for your credit card number). If you make a donation through an individual fundraising page associated with a fundraising team, or directly to a team fundraising page, then the team fundraising captain will also have access to your Personal Information (again, except for your credit card number). You consent to the foregoing and agree that we are not responsible for how these organizations or persons handle your Personal Information. You should visit their websites and/or contact them directly for their privacy policies and data usage practices. 

##  What's an individual profile? 

When you make a transaction through the Website, we automatically index it for you in an individual profile specific to you. That information remains hidden from the public. If you activate your profile, then you will be able to see your profile when you are logged in. The information in your profile remains inaccessible to the public after you activate it; in order to prevent unauthorized access to your profile, you should not share your login information with other people. 

##  What is a charity profile? 

Each nonprofit that registers with the Website is automatically created a charity profile. This profile displays the nonprofit's active events, campaigns, and projects (unless they've been made "private"). It also displays the total amount the nonprofit has raised through the Website and total number of supporters. Each charity profile also includes an activity feed that displays activity occurring on the Website related to that charity (e.g. donations made, events posted, etc.). Charity profiles are public. They can be located by using the search within the Website or by external search engines. 

##  Are pages I create private? 

In general, no. If you create a personal fundraising page, team page, an event page, campaign page, donation page, "get involved page," or other webpage on the Website, it is not private. Pages created on the Website are indexed by search engines and accessible to the public. 

If you create an event or campaign on the Website and select the "private" setting, this means that the event or campaign link will not be displayed through the activity feeds on the Website, the event or campaign will not be available through the internal search function on the Website, and it will not be indexed by external search engines like Google. It does not mean, however, that people cannot still wind up on your page (e.g. if the link is shared with them). Please keep in mind that, even if you make a campaign or event private, any personal fundraising pages created by your supporters as part of that campaign or event will remain publicly accessible. 

##  What other information is public? 

Information you post on event pages, campaign pages, personal fundraising pages, a charity profile, blog posts, or other public pages on the Website can be accessed by other people. You should exercise caution when deciding to share information on public pages. We cannot control who accesses shared information or how other parties will use that information. 

##  What are activity feeds? 

Activity feeds are streamed displays of actions occurring on the Website. There are various public activity feeds on the Website. Charity profiles have activity feeds that display activity relevant to each respective charity (e.g. donations to, or ticket purchases from, that organization). 

Unless you select the option to donate anonymously, your name and the amount of your donation (or ticket/registration purchase) will be publicly displayed through the relevant charity profile's activity feed and the activity feed of a fundraising or team page 

Nonprofits using the Website also have access to certain widgets (widgets are small snippets of code we generate that the nonprofit can then put into another website). These widgets allow a nonprofit to display activity occurring on the Website on the nonprofit's own website, blog, or another website. Unless you donate anonymously, your name and the amount of your donation (or ticket/registration purchase) may be publicly displayed through the activity feed on a widget. If you become a supporter of a nonprofit on the Website, or fundraise for a nonprofit on the Website, your name and picture may also be displayed on a widget. Please keep in mind that we cannot control, where a given nonprofit will embed the widgets we make accessible to it. 

##  What are API's and how can my information be shared? 

We make an application programming interface (an " **API** ") available to nonprofit clients. An API (in non technical terms) allows a nonprofit to automatically retrieve information from our site, for use/display elsewhere (e.g. on the nonprofit's website). To give an example, a nonprofit might use our API to retrieve the names and photos of the top 5 fundraisers for a campaign it is running; the nonprofit could then display that information on a leader board on its own website. If you are fundraising for a nonprofit your name, picture, amount raised, and goal, can be retrieved by the nonprofit through our API. If you create a team fundraising page, then your name, the team goal, and the amount raised by the team can also be retrieved by the nonprofit through our API. If you host an event for a charity, then your name, contact info, and the location of your event can be retrieved by the benefitting nonprofit through our API. The foregoing examples are for illustrative purposes only. The nonprofit you engage with has access to other information through our API such as tickets sold, number of attendees, etc. That being said, the information that we make available through our API is (generally) information that is otherwise available on the Website (e.g. already posted on an event page, campaign page, available through search results, etc.). 

##  What choices do I have? 

It's up to you whether or not you want to provide us with Personal Information. You can still visit the Website without providing us with Personal information, but you will be unable to take certain actions without doing so. 

You can also choose to make contributions anonymously. If you make an anonymous contribution, your name will not be displayed through the Website's activity feeds and your Personal Information will not be given to (i) the individual fundraiser you made a donation through, or (ii) the team fundraising captain if you donated through a team fundraising page or a personal page associated with a fundraising team. 

##  How can I update or correct my Personal Information? 

If you have activated your profile you can update your information by clicking on "Account Settings" which is accessible at the top of your screen once you've logged in. 

##  What do I do if my information is lost or stolen? 

If you know, or suspect, that your credit card, user name, or password has been lost, stolen, or used without your authorization you need to contact us immediately ([help@classy.org](mailto:help@classy.org)). Upon notification, we will take reasonable steps to mitigate any damage which may have been caused. You are responsible for the safety and security of your user name and password. You should logout after each session you have with the Website and you shouldn't share this information. 

##  Can Children Use this Website? 

Our Website is for a general audience and is not targeted towards children. Children under 13 years of age are prohibited from using the Website per our Terms of Service. If your child has used the Website and submitted Personal Information to us, please contact us and we will endeavor to remove that information from the Website and our database.
